ird.govt.nz 2003-06-05

# Privacy policy

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. This privacy policy tells you:

  * you can browse our website without providing personal information;
  * what personal information we collect;
  * what rights you have in relation to the personal information we hold;
  * who can access your personal information;
  * how long we will keep your personal information; and
  * how you can contact us if you have queries or concerns about our privacy policy.

### You can browse our website without providing personal information

You can access our website homepage and browse our site without disclosing your personal information.

In particular:

  * we do not use cookies on this website (a cookie is a piece of information that a website sends to your browser when you access information at that site);
  * we do not automatically record personal information; and
  * we do not link information that is recorded automatically with personal information about specific individuals.

Please note that the Online Correspondence Service collects and stores personal information provided during the registration process and details of the correspondence sent and received.

### We automatically record some non-personal information

We do not attempt to identify users or their browsing activities unless they choose to provide us with personal information.

If you visit our website to read or download information, we automatically record some non-personal information, for example:

  * the type of browser you use;
  * the type of operating system you use;
  * the date and time you access our site;
  * the pages you have accessed and the documents downloaded; 
  * the internet address from which you accessed our site; and
  * the last site you visited before you accessed any Inland Revenue website.

The above information is used to create summary statistics that allow us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, discover what information is most and least used, determine technical design specifications, and help us make our site more useful to visitors.

Please note that we may collect additional information (including personal information) if we believe a user is attempting to compromise our website.

### What personal information do we collect?

We collect personal information when:

  * you fill in an Inland Revenue online form;
  * you subscribe to a service or newsletter; or
  * you correspond with us.

### Online forms

You can provide personal information to us by filling in an Inland Revenue online form.

Before you submit the form to us, you will be asked to confirm that the information you have supplied is true and correct. This information is used to update our main database and is then part of your Inland Revenue records.

We may share the information you provide with other Government Agencies who are entitled to the information under legislation. Please read the privacy statement at the end of each online form.

### Subscribing to a service or newsletter

If you subscribe to a service or newsletter through this website, we record your email address in a database. We use your email address to send you the service or newsletter. We will not disclose your email address to any third parties without your consent.

### Corresponding with us

You can provide us with personal information by corresponding with us. We may use this information for the purpose you supplied it to us. We may use this information to update our database or your tax records. We may share the information you provide with other Government Agencies who are entitled to the information under legislation.

### What rights do you have in relation to your personal information?

You can access the personal information we hold about you as part of your Inland Revenue records. Please call us on 0800 377 774 and request a copy of your personal information and we will provide you with a copy of the personal information we keep about you. We may require proof of your identity before we provide you with this information

If you consider that some of the information we hold about you is incorrect, you can request us to change the information. We will assess your request and will either change the relevant information, or explain why we think the information should not be changed and make a note of your change request on your records.

### Who can access your personal information?

We do not disclose your personal information to other visitors to our website.

We may be required by legislation to share information with other Government agencies. We will not disclose your personal information to any non-Inland Revenue person unless required by law.

### How long will we keep your personal information?

We will keep your personal information for as long as necessary to achieve the purpose for which we collected it. If your personal information becomes part of your Inland Revenue records, we will retain the information in accordance with Inland Revenue policy on retention of Inland Revenue records.

### Privacy policy queries and concerns

If you have any queries or concerns about our privacy policy please contact:

The Privacy Officer  
Inland Revenue National Office  
Box 2198  
Wellington  
New Zealand

Email [privacy.officer@ird.govt.nz](mailto:privacy.officer@ird.govt.nz)

If you are not satisfied with our response to your concern, you can contact the Privacy Commissioner:

Office of the Privacy Commissioner  
PO Box 10094  
Wellington

Phone 0800 803 909  
Fax 04 474 7590
